A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007 FA451
Rockefeller Archive Center
John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
1906-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison), 1906-1978
Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker
FA451
25 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate.
Approximately 3,000 prints and contact prints.
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
The JDR 3rd family photographs, Series 1007, are further arranged by format type: prints, albums and oversized, with the images primarily arranged by type or subject.
Other Finding Aids
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA446 William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA449 John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA454 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Series 1008
FA452 Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
This collection of photographs contains indivdiual and group portraits of JDR 3rd and family, as well as informal and candid shots. Also documented are JDR 3rd's Asia activities primarily in Japan, philanthropic activities and events, travel, and a small selection of images of JDR 3rd with various dignitaries.
Photographs
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, 1007
  Arrangement
  For ease of access the material is further arranged by:
  Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Albums (Boxes A 1, A 2, A 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, C 1, C 2, C 3 etc.).
  - Prints, 1292 prints and contact sheets.
    - Alida Davison Rockefeller - Coming Out Party, 1967; 70 prints, color (Box P 166, Folder 1)
    - Alida Davison Rockefeller Messenger, 1951; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 2)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Permission is required in order to publish or otherwise use photographs and other visual materials of living members of the Rockefeller family. See RAC Head of Reference for details.
      RAC users must abide by all applicable provisions of United States copyright law.
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1931-1961; 8 prints (Box P 133)
      Scope and Contents
      Portraits
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 3)
      Portrait
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Portrait - Bradford Bachrach, 1968; 4 prints (Box P 166, Folder 4)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Portraits - Newspapers, 1974; 6 prints (Box P 166, Folder 5)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Portraits - O.E. Nelson, 1975 December; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 6)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1932-1955; 10 prints (Box P 133)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 3 prints (Box P 166, Folder 7)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 3 prints (Box P 166, Folder 7A)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Asia Society - Bernard Wolf (Box P 166, Folder 8)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Family Weekly, 1974; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 9)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Honeymoon in Bermuda, 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 10)
    - Group Portraits - Family - JDR 3rd Memorial Service, 1978; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 11)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Last Photo of JDR 3rd and Blanchette, 1978; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 12)
    - Group Portraits - Family - JDR 3rd and Blanchette - JDR IV Inauguration, 1977; 10 prints (Box P 166, Folder 13)
    - Homes, 1936; 1 print (Box P 133)
      East River front
    - Hope Aldrich Rockefeller Spencer, 13 prints (Box P 166, Folder 14)
    - Hope Aldrich Rockefeller Spencer, 1955; 3 prints (Box P 166, Folder 15)
    - Hope Aldrich Rockefeller Spencer, 1959; 4 prints (Box P 166, Folder 16)
      Wedding
    - JDR 3rd - Album - Kosetsart University, 1963; 40 prints (Box P 166, Folder 17)
    - JDR 3rd - Alleghany Conference, 1961; 5 prints (Box P 133)
      Pittsburgh, PA
    - JDR 3rd - Art - American Art Collection Gift to Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco, 1978; 51 prints (Box P 166, Folder 18)
    - JDR 3rd - Art - American Art Collection Gift to Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco (Photocopies), 1978 (Box P 166, Folder 19)
      Photocopies only
    - JDR 3rd - Art - American Art Collection Gift to Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco - Informals, 1978; 16 prints (Box P 166, Folder 20)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Asia Society - Asia House - Opening, 1959; 15 prints (Box P 166, Folder 21)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Asia Society - Masayoshi Ohira, 1979; 3 prints (Box P 166, Folder 22)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - India, 2 prints (Box P 133)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - India - Desai Reception, 1962; 5 prints (Box P 133)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan, 4 prints (Box P 166, Folder 23)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Ambassador Araki, 1952; 16 prints (Box P 133)
      Dinner by Japan Society
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Dulles Peace Mission, 1951; 3 prints (Box P 133)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Japan Society, 1953; 2 prints (Box P 133)
      Miss Ayako Tomii, University of Pennsylvania student.
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Japanese-American Relations Awards, 1960; 2 prints (Box P 133)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Miscellaneous, 1947-1969; 14 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Museum of Modern Art (MOMA) Japanese House, 1953-1954; 6 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Premier Yoshida Reception, 1954; 8 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Trip, 1951; 5 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Trip, 1952; 6 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Trip, 1958; 7 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan - Trip, 1962; 4 prints (Box P 134)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Korea, 1965; 2 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Laos, 1959; 8 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Philippines, 1957; 1 print (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Philippines - Botanical Gardens, 1967; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 24)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Thailand, 1957-1960; 3 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Vietnam, 1957-1964; 2 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Candids, 1967; 2 prints (Box P 166, Folder 25)
    - JDR 3rd - Columbia, 1964; 3 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries - Haile Selassie, 1954; 8 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries - King and Queen of Afghanistan, 1963; 7 prints (Box P 135)
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries - Emperor Hirohito - Empresses Nagako, 1975; 4 prints (Box P 166, Folder 26)
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries - Indira Gandhi - B.K. Nehru - NY Times, 1966 March 30; 2 prints (Box P 166, Folder 27)
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries - JFK, 1958; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 28)
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries - Thailand - Field Marshall Pibulsonggram, 1957; 1 print (Box P 166, Folder 29)
    - JDR 3rd - Government Service - Commission on Population Growth and the American Future, 1971; 6 prints (Box P 167, Folder 30)
    - JDR 3rd - Government Service - Committee on Population and Family Planning - LBJ, 1969; 2 prints (Box P 167, Folder 31)
    - JDR 3rd - Informals, 1961; 2 prints (Box P 167, Folder 32)
    - JDR 3rd - Informals, 1969; 6 prints (Box P 167, Folder 33)
    - JDR 3rd - Informals, 1969; 2 prints (Box P 167, Folder 34)
    - JDR 3rd - Informals - Fieldwood Farm, 1977; 36 contact prints (Box P 167, Folder 35)
    - JDR 3rd - Joint Civilian Orientation Conference, 1952; 5 prints (Box P 136)
      Aboard USS Sperry, US Naval Air Station, Pensacola, FL
    - JDR 3rd - Miscellaneous, 1954-1969; 23 prints (Box P 136)
    - JDR 3rd - National Committee on United States-China Relations, 1969; 2 prints (Box P 137)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies, 1949-1957; 25 prints (Box P 137)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Arkansas Art Center, 1962; 7 prints (Box P 138)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Asia Society - Prince Akihito - Colonial Williamsburg, 1953; 5 prints (Box P 167, Folder 36-37)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Colonial Williamsburg - Kenneth Chorley, 1949; 1 print (Box P 167, Folder 38)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Associates, 1 print (Box P 138)
      Robert F. Goheen, President, Princeton University
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - General Education Board - Texas, 1947; 69 prints (Box P 167, Folder 39)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Greater New York Fund, 1949; 2 prints (Box P 138)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - India International House, 1962; 8 prints (Box P 138)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - India International House, 1962; 1 print (Box P 167, Folder 40)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - International Rice Research Center (IRRC), 1962-1971; 8 prints (Box P 138)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Japan Society - Dinner, 1952; 3 prints (Box P 167, Folder 41)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Japan Society - Yoshida, 1954; 6 prints (Box P 167, Folder 42)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - JDR 3rd Fund - Arts in Education, 1969; 3 prints (Box P 167, Folder 43)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - JDR 3rd Youth Award, 1976; 1 print (Box P 167, Folder 44)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center, 1959-1970; 24 prints (Box P 139)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center, 1955-1970; 30 prints (Box P 140)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center, 2 prints (Box P 167, Folder 45)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center, 20 prints (Box P 167, Folder 46)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Dedication, 1963; 41 prints (Box P 167, Folder 47)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Dedication, 1963; 4 contact sheets (Box P 167, Folder 48)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Julliard School, 11 prints (Box P 167, Folder 49)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - King and Queen of Thailand, 1967 June 13; 12 prints (Box P 167, Folder 50)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Leonard Bernstein - Jackie Kennedy, 1962; 1 print and 6 additional copies. (Box P 167, Folder 51)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Lincoln Square Before Demolition, 18 prints (Box P 167, Folder 52)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Metropolitan Opera House, 17 prints (Box P 167, Folder 53)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Philharmonic Hall, 5 prints (Box P 167, Folder 54)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center - Pre-Opening Performance, 1964; 5 prints (Box P 167, Folder 55)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Phelps Memorial Hospital, 1956; 10 prints (Box P 141)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1957-1959; 20 prints (Box P 141)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Archive Center, 1980; 1 print (Box P 142)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Foundation, 1946-1963; 5 prints (Box P 142)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Foundation - Mexico, 1946; 2 prints (Box P 167, Folder 56)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Public Service Award, 1958-1962; 9 prints (Box P 142)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Public Service Award - Blanchette and Jay, 1978; 1 print (Box P 167, Folder 57)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - United Nations, 1969; 1 print (Box P 167, Folder 58)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Williamsburg, c. 1940-1950; 6 prints (Box P 142)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 1929-1956; 41 prints (Box P 143)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 1931-1969; 29 prints and additional contact sheets (Box P 144)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 12 prints (Box P 168, Folder 59)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 2 prints (Box P 168, Folder 59A)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 10 prints (Box P 168, Folder 60)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 1 print (Box P 168, Folder 61)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 1948; 12 prints (Box P 168, Folder 62)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman, 30 prints (Box P 168, Folder 63)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman, 1969; 30 prints and contact sheets (Box P 168, Folder 64)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman #25, 1969; 7 prints including duplicates (Box P 168, Folder 65)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman - Master Prints, 1969; 13 prints (Box P 168, Folder 66)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman - Original Proofs and Master Prints, 1964; 8 prints (Box P 168, Folder 67)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman, 4 prints including duplicates (Box P 169, Folder 82)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Arnold Newman, 32 prints including duplicates (Box P 169, Folder 83)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Chairman of the Commission on Population Growth and the American Future, 1972; 11 prints (Box P 168, Folder 68)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Ehrenford, 2 prints (Box P 168, Folder 69)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Fabian Bachrach, 2 prints (Box P 168, Folder 70)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Fabian Bachrach, 6 prints (Box P 168, Folder 71)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 5 prints (Box P 168, Folder 72)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 13 prints (Box P 168, Folder 73)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 5 prints (Box P 168, Folder 74)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 18 prints (Box P 168, Folder 75)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 6 prints (Box P 168, Folder 76)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 5 prints (Box P 168, Folder 77)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 3 prints (Box P 168, Folder 78)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Gabor Eder, 1 print (Box P 168, Folder 79)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Joseph Heppner, 3 prints (Box P 169, Folder 80)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Metropolitan Photo Service, 15 prints (Box P 169, Folder 81)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - New York Times, 1956; 1 print (Box P 169, Folder 84)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - New York Times, 1956; 2 prints (Box P 169, Folder 85)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - New York Times, 1956; 1 print (Box P 169, Folder 87)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Painting, 5 prints (Box P 169, Folder 88)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Second American Revolution, 1973; 5 prints (Box P 169, Folder 89)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Second American Revolution - Contact Sheets, 1973; 2 contact sheets (Box P 169, Folder 90)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - University of Michigan, 1967; 4 prints (Box P 169, Folder 91)
    - JDR 3rd - Princeton - Board of Trustees, 1961; 1 print (Box P 169, Folder 92)
    - JDR IV, 10 prints (Box P 169, Folder 93)
    - JDR IV, 15 prints and 5 contact sheets (Box P 169, Folder 94)
    - JDR IV - Wedding to Sharon Lee Percy, 27 contact prints (Box P 169, Folder 95)
    - Relatives - Mrs. Elon Huntington Hooker, 1 print (Box P 169, Folder 96)
    - Sandra Ferry Rockefeller, 2 prints (Box P 169, Folder 97)
  - Albums, Approximately 1,560 prints
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Homes - 620 Park Avenue, 1942 May; 13 prints (Box A 23)
      Photographs by Sandra Fuehr
    - JDR 3rd - Childhood (1), 121 prints (Box A 1)
    - JDR 3rd - Childhood (2), 124 prints (Box A 2)
    - JDR 3rd - Childhood (3), 375 prints (Box A 3)
    - JDR 3rd Album, 1925-1934, 82 prints (Box A 4)
    - JDR 3rd Album, 1933-1945, 55 prints (Box A 5)
    - JDR 3rd Album, 1946-1951, 52 prints (Box A 6)
    - JDR 3rd Album, 1952-1959, 50 prints (Box A 7)
    - JDR 3rd Album, 1959-1967, 50 prints (Box A 8)
    - JDR 3rd Album, 1967-1976, 38 prints (Box A 9)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Thailand - Thai Fine Arts Department, 1962; 43 prints (Box A 10)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - "The International House of Japan Under Construction", 1954; 29 prints (Box A 13)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - "Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts", 1959-1969; 24 prints (Box A 14)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center Model, 9 prints (Box A 22)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Foundation - "The Rockefeller Foundation Board of Trustees - 50th Anniversary Meeting", 1963 April 3; 12 prints (Box A 15)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Rockefeller Foundation - "Mexican Agricultural Program of the Rockefeller Foundation", 40 prints (Box A 16)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - United Nations - "Title Closing, United Nations Capitol Site", 1947 March 25; 16 prints (Box A 17)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - "The Story in Prose and in Pictures of the 12th Annual Campaign of the Greater New York Fund", 1949; Approximately 50 images (Box A 20)
      Scrapbook
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Koshiba Proofs, 22 prints (Box A 11)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits - Business Week and Life Magazine, 38 prints (Box A 12)
    - JDR 3rd - Travel - "Mexico", 1946; 47 prints (Box A 13A)
    - JDR 3rd - Travel - Visit to Pakistan, 1968 February; 32 prints (Box A 18)
    - JDR 3rd - Travel - West Pakistan Family Planning Board, Lahore, 1968 February 6-7; 35 prints (Box A 19)
      Photos taken by Nahid Rana of Sweden Pakistan Family Welfare Project, Lahore
    - JDR 3rd - Travel - "Trip through the American West", 1924; Approximately 200 prints (Box A 21)
  - Oversized, 162 prints
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller Family, 14 prints (Box O 1)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - "Blanchette's pictures of Barbara", 16 prints (Box O 2)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - "Blanchette's pictures of Mother", 11 prints (Box O 3)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Portraits, 19 prints including duplicates (Box O 4)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Portraits, 19 prints including duplicates (Box O 5)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller - Portraits, 19 prints including duplicates (Box O 6)
    - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller family, 11 prints (Box O 9)
    - Group Portraits - Family - Brothers, 1 print (Box O 11)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Japan, 1951; 1 print (Box O 7)
    - JDR 3rd - Asia - Laos, 23 prints (Box O 10)
    - JDR 3rd - Business, 1957; 1 print (Box O 7)
      New York Life Insurance Board
    - JDR 3rd - Dignitaries, 1 print (Box O 7)
    - JDR 3rd - Informals, 1950, 1961; 4 prints (Box O 7)
    - JDR 3rd - Miscellaneous, 1950; 1 print (Box O 7)
      With George Marshall
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies (Box C 6)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies, 1 print (Box O 7)
    - JDR 3rd - Philanthropies - Lincoln Center, 5 prints (Box O 11)
    - JDR 3rd - Portraits, 4 prints (Box O 7)
    - Population, 1967-1969; 10 prints (Box O 8)